HI, I AM MADELEINE KINGSLEY

PHONE: 0481 259 281 EMAIL ADDRESS:

maddiekingsley1209@gmail.com

ADDRESS: Toowong, Brisbane WEBSITE: madeleinekingsley.com

Graduating from the University of Queensland in July 2016 with a Bachelor of Information Technology, I have been working for three years in industry where I have explored and gained knowledge about the diverse landscape of technology and design. My more refined skills are designing for iOS and Android interfaces and sparking conversations with people. Whether that's getting out and engaging with our audience or building company culture within the office.

Over the past three years, the majority of my experience has matured within two start-ups. Small companies specialising in education and the payments space, in a setting where I have usually been the only designer. I consider myself an all-rounder person, as I juggled 2 jobs for the last year and a half. My experience ranges the communication of ideas and concepts to students and teams, iterating constantly on visual designs all the way through to deployment. I look forward to possible future work presented to me as I continue to gain experience and commence my career.

EDUCATION

2013 -16 UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND | Bachelor of Information Technology

Graphic Design | Human Computer Interaction | Interactive Design |
Physical Computing | Design Computing | Web Design | Creative Thinking

2010-11 MOUNTAIN CREEK STATE HIGH SCHOOL

2008-10 JAKARTA INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL, INDONESIA

EXPERIENCE

2018 PRODUCT DESIGNER | SNIP

Sniip is a FinTech company that has developed a digital payment option where customers can scan a QR or BPAY code to pay their bill.

Sniip is a Brisbane based company where I have been from July, 2018 until December, 2019. Tasks and duties delegated to me expanded the end to end product and customer experience. Starting with discovery and ending with testing and approval of development into production, relying heavily on stories and prototypes in between.

- Conduct user research and testing. Usability Testing, Interviews.
- Working the support desk and providing support to users
- Designing deliverables including; Process flows, wireframes, visual designs, documenting requirements
- Creating UI deliverables including; Customer research,
 Market/Competitor research, Customer personas, Experience map
- Performing shoulder checks and testing of products following an agile process
- As a member of the agile delivery team to support design, elaborate and test mobile and web products
- Creating style guides to define UI elements;
- Document test cases and work closes with developers to test all environments of the app
- Perform manual testing on mobile and web applications
- Identify and document defects
- Support test automation development
- Attending, contributing and providing updates in standard agile meetings; elaboration, estimation, daily stand-up, retrospective
- Contributing ideas for future product features and opportunities
- Taking and giving constructively critques
- Gather and understand business requirements through preparing and facilitating small workshops
- Occasional general graphic design support to the marketing department including website support & presentation materials

2018 TUTOR | THE UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND

UQ's School of Information Technology and Electrical Engineering is at the leading-edge of information and communications technology.

REFEREES

Stephen Viller
Director of Coursework Studies,
UQ Interaction Design Group
viller@itee.uq.edu.au

Pem Deuchen
Partner, Momentum Cloud
0402 956 111
pem.deuchen@momentumcloud.com.au

Alistair Cornish CTO, Sniip 0447 407 159 alistair.cornish@sniip.com

Lorna Macdonald Lecturer in Interaction Design at UQ lorna@itee.uq.edu.au Throughout my time at UQ, I tutored and helped created content for three design courses. Tutoring has presented a series of different challenges. Many of which have helped me become a confident public speaker and relearn foundational theories.

DECO3500 - Social & Mobile Computing

DECO3800 - Design Computing Studio 3: Proposal

DECO2500 - Human-Computer Interaction

- Reinforced ability to communicate clearly, logically, and creatively
- Exposed to different learning styles from different course coordinators
- Became aware of my own personal learning style
- Marking and critiquing students work
- Working closely with course coordinators to help refine and iterate on course content and structure

2016 UI/UX DESIGNER | MOMENTUM CLOUD

Momentum Cloud is a software company that creates goal based products to help build learning support and empower individuals to achieve their very best.

I started working for Momentum Cloud in November of 2016 until March 2018. My role focused on designing functionality for a piece of software called MyPLgoals as well as development of an app called MGoals.

- Showed management and problem solving skills when fixing unforeseen problems within the software
- Have traits of being a natural leader, as I excel at leading people and projects with a strategic and creative approach, finding user-centred solutions to complex problems.
- MyPLgoals is complex, multi-dimensional product that covers aspects of business models to Government procedures, therefore I learnt how to design for content heavy applications.
- Created new processes by introducing InVision App into the UX process and a software called Zeplin, to close the gap between design and development team.
- Became a clearer and stronger communicator to advocate my design ideas, thought processes and research notes.
- Helped team members prioritized work with ticketing systems (JIRA) and Kanban boards as well as working on product roadmaps.
- Worked with Angular is to develop the functionality designed

2016 FRONT END DEVELOPER | THE GRUDEN GROUP

Gruden is an award winning, leading digital services company that builds customer facing digital assets.

- Taking designs into rapid development of UI for a large digital product/platform
- Liaising with UI and UX project members to release the UI quickly for feedback and approval.
- Constant communication with other front end technical developers, to ensure styles, look and functionality are implemented correctly.